um so I'm going to move swiftly on um
our first speaker is Roman granov um
Roman's an old you're an old friend Pac
You' spoken at this you spoken at mice's
other conferences um and he describes
himself as a a principal ml engineer and
an ex startup
CTO you never remember the bio you
submit later on um working on Modern
search and Rec and recommendation um
Roman's always an entertaining speaker
so please put your hands together for
ran hello my name is Raman and today
we're going to speak about
non-traditional ways of running search
over blog storage why would you ever do
this how we started up uh building a
small prototype to prove that this idea
is actually workable and ended up
building a search engine like a
serverless search engine you can
actually use from time to time a couple
of uh words about myself I'm coming from
Academia through different areas of
machine learning and for the last many
years I'm working in eCommerce search
originally at findify uh with a focus on
ranking
personalization and currently at
delivery Hero on food search through all
this modern embeddings and llms and all
that things uh I'm also maintaining a
couple of Open Source projects which are
slightly related to ranking and
personalization tasks but this talk is
not going to be about embedding models
personalization ranking and LTR because
uh I call this some sort of a conference
hangover when you got inspired with all
this modern Technologies modern uh
breakthrough methods of doing ranking
and all that things and you come back to
work and you start spinning this wheel
of reality of operating your search
engine which actually generates Revenue
which pays your salary and this is this
is picture started as original as a joke
but it actually summarizes all the
incidents I got with a ating search
engines and it's not not about a
specific particular search engine it's
more about the whole class of search
engines we currently run in the
production and uh this can be all
summarized that search engines are
considered special so it's uh more
database is search engine actually a
database a stateful application which
depends on Pern note storage it's has a
problems of up and down scaling because
you need to do this state rebalance if
something goes bad with your storage is
also gos broken and the state inside is
encapsulated of in your application
can't really figure out if things got uh
bad uh but if you reflect back and see
what's usually happening with backend
applications it's all usually rainbows
and unicorns because you have your um
application your computer separated from
your state you can do all this modern
roll backs uh Blu green deployments AB
tests all this scale UPS TA down and
it's much easier to observe operate and
modify because the state is not managed
by you that's the wonderful thing and
it's easier to modify and understand
because if your state is lying in
postgress you can just go there and see
what's going on there to do any data
migrations backups and it's much
convenient uh but the issue with the
current search engines that this state
this complexity is not only uh locked
inside of the search engine it also goes
uh beyond that into your search and
indexing pipeline so if you state change
something in your index you also need to
update this pipeline which just increase
the overall complexity of operating your
search engine if I was a search engine
vendor I will Embrace complexity because
it helps me to save my manage services
but I'm more like an operator of this
search servers so I'm trying to reduce
complexity to make my life easier as an
operator and you might wonder that okay
I'm going to move to the idea of should
this search be stateless and more like a
backend application and less like a
database and there are a couple of
projects which are already doing it so
in Lucine World there is an enert search
which is a Yelp search engine which is
not particularly popular aart used
inside of yel but it's open source you
can go on a GitHub and see how it's done
it's implemented on top of Luc near real
time
replication open search can also do
something like this with a segment
replication over remote storage but it's
not about fully stateless search but at
least you offload your index somewhere
which is already good in a nonline world
there is quick WID which is a search
engine over for logs and traces and
Telemetry which is not usable as a
general purposed search Lang uh search
engine but it's tied like a competitor
to the E key stack and there is also
close Source turbo puffer which is like
a vector search engine which runs over
block storage directly and the main
point of all these search engines that
if you decouple your search your compute
and your storage you'll get easy
operations and it's much cheaper to run
because you are not tied to be overr
provisioning your cluster because it's
so scary to scale it up or scale it down
uh and if you go for the industry it's
that's the direction industry also takes
uh so it started all with this Amazon
talk on Buzz Wars many years ago about
how the search works and it's all about
indexer being decoupled from uh the
whole search pipeline you have indexer
which updates segments on S3 and there
are Searchers which are picking the
segments you go for door Dash
publication and you see the same uh
picture it's actually from the door Dash
publication as far as I know and the
same for Uber and even me in my past
company also was INSP were inspired by
this publication by Amazon and migrated
from Les from like a search engine like
elastic search to Lucine and we're quite
happy with this but if you want to if
you wonder do this search engines are
actually open source no that's not the
case so if you want to do something like
this you have to be on your own and
usually that's what companies choose but
uh that's how Nixie search was born so
like okay there is a demand in the
industry why don't we just write our own
search engine yes it sounds like a very
stupid IDE in 2024
but we are not afraid of stupid ideas so
it started as a proof of concept for
doing like a search uh with Lucine over
block storage ended up a bit more than
that but if you go over Lucine and block
storage and do some Curious archaeology
you'll find a blog post by Kim CH was
sha Bannon It's actually an author of
elastic search and now SEO of elastic so
when he found out that S3 it's like 15
years ago uh but S3 is so wonderful so
that we should actually maybe use Lucine
on top of us three but it haven't
finished up by like elastic or comass at
that time to be run on S3 but uh is it
hard to extend Lucine in a way to work
over some non-traditional block storage
and actually yes because Lucine has a
directory interface which describes how
you do input an output with your storage
some sort of an abstraction there are
nice and popular abstractions like a
memory map directory you're probably
using there is a bite buffers directory
if you want to have everything in memory
there are some directories you shouldn't
really using like gdbc directory but
they do exist if you Google and but the
issue the main perk of having this
directory interface is that's the whole
interface like seven methods Reading
Writing moving deleting and so on so
it's very trivial in maps to semantic of
remote block storage like S3 and S3 I
don't uh mean like it's an Amazon S3 S3
is more like a protocol because Google
Cloud also implements S3 protocol you
can self host it with Mino all the
smaller Cloud providers like lenot ovh
also provide this S3 compatible uh blog
storages for you so it's not about
Amazon but we're going to speak mostly
about this Amazon implementation and you
don't really need to go that far because
if you Google Lucina 3 director you'll
find one implemented by Alex banovski
and it's like tight like it's very
experiment don't use it uh because uh
you might wonder that Lucine was
designed in a way that it works with a
block storage with is just close to you
it's on a local drive and Amazon's S3 is
very very far away and for nvme Laten
you have 0.1 millisecond and for Amazon
it's like 10 to 20 millisecond there is
even a benchmark stating that it's very
bad like 16 seconds for quiry which is
kind of a bit even more than you can
wait but after read sources and with
this directory which directly just goes
to S3 on any read um or right we thought
that maybe we can go a bit smarter than
that maybe Lucine directory Lucine index
is having some sort of hotpots you don't
really need to go for the second time
for a Blog you can cach it locally
that's what we actually did so we did
some sort of a proxy for Lo like a
street directory which is cached locally
so if the segment was not re not not
never was read you just go for the S3
and cach it locally if you reading it
for the second time you just do right
through read through caching and get it
from the dis so no storage no it's like
stateless notes it's easy to scale up
scale down everything know three but
they're still going to be latency
especially on the first requests and how
how hard how big is this latency if you
going to access S3 on Amazon there are
actually two S3 implementations through
two S3 in points the first one is more
like a traditional endpoint and the
second one is S3 Express which is non-
redundant non Geor replicated but it's
much faster so we did a couple of
benchmarks and it seems to be that first
bite latency it doesn't really depend on
the Block size you can run WBY you can
read one megabyte it's going to be the
same 20 milliseconds for S3 and actually
just 5 milliseconds for S3 Express for
the cost of reduced redundancy but you
might agree to pay this thing uh if you
want and for the last bite latency it
looks very flat so it technically the
overall latency request latency is just
this first five or 20 millisecond for
the actual round trip to S3 API and then
some transfer on the top which doesn't
really depend on the Block size it's
just your throat putut and so after
doing this type of cashing directory
implementation we wanted to do actually
a practical experiment that's nice that
you can run it but is it worth it at the
end so we took Ms Marco data set with
different sizes of document sample and
did some sort of vector search over this
block storage implementation with 700
dimensions and just a single segment for
the sake of uh Simplicity with the
default Lucine settings for doing this
Vector search and the main option that
you you you might remember that it's
this thing how many links your node in
hnv graph has because I'm going to
reference this is going to be quite
important a couple of next slides and
that's the numbers we got there are a
lot of numbers but the most interesting
thing I'm going to Dear it so there are
three like small index medium index
large index for 1 million documents
different block sizes and this is how
many reads we did to S3 to make first
request and uh given this latency for
the last bite for this type request
you'll get this final latency for first
request it might be okay for a third 30
megabyte index but we actually doing the
just the first request over this number
of requests to S3 with this block size
you read onethird of the index just
doing first request H suspicious if we
go uh further for the large index we do
a hoping like 300 requests to S3 just to
do the first search request so much and
it rels to 3 second latency for the
first request doesn't seem to be very
nice that's not what you're getting
proudly present on a conference but what
that's what I do 3 seconds latency if
you search over S3 you might wonder okay
the first request it's not that bad
maybe it's getting better for the second
request for the third request it's
getting
like like much much better but
unfortunately ah so why it's going on
like this because it's Vector search
because it's hnv and you are not doing
like a traditional lexical search when
you got your query go to the inverted
index just get a list of documents read
the you're done in hnv it's a graft
reversal so got your quiry you got into
this graph here here's your quiry you
got this into the graph and each note in
the graph 16 links and you're going to
evaluate like assign distance between
your quiry and all the 16 neighbors and
each evaluation each probe is actually a
random rate of 5 to 10 milliseconds and
then you do it iteratively by doing to
layer traversal lest graph doing this a
ton of different sequential random
rats uh and it's not getting better if
you do it for the request and for the
30th request because on 30th request
it's like around 1 second which is still
very bad and at the moment when you do
do 30 requests which should be enough to
warm up your index you already read like
30% of the whole 1 million document
index so it doesn't seem to be very
reasonable approach and that's a like a
very old MIM coming from Russia I tried
to translate it so you can build
something very stupid from a Loa of
bread but
why yeah so that's what we actually
built and um but uh you can do better
because if you're following Lucine uh
imple Lucine development currently there
is an interesting umbrella ticket called
improve Lucine ioon Curren there's a lot
of different discussions going on it's
targeted for Lucine 10 which is going to
be event released but some sort of tldr
what's it's about improving our
concurrency Lucine itself is not
concurrent it's just you know for this
graph reversal it's just a collection of
four Loops so there is no concurrency
happening at all but you can do
concurrency on the iio level so instead
of so when we do this hnv graph reversal
we have a node and 16 neighbors we need
to evaluate for the 16 neighbors we need
16 read operations for all this uh uh
vectors to do this cosine distance
similarity and you do 16 times back and
forth to F3 this uh pull request
actually introduces a prefet method
which can you can call and say by the
way soon I'm going to read this 16 uh
blocks from the storage and you can do
whatever you want with this and by
default it can be just ignored but from
our case when you have a huge latency
for this going back and forth to block
storage you can actually start
prefetching all 16 at the moment when
you actually started Ann announced that
you're going to do it and Lucine as S3
is actually has not that good latency
but a very good concurrency it's almost
perfect concurrency so for example if
you scale number of requests till 16
you'll just max out your networking
interface and practice even on small
notes you can fetch one gigabyte per
second from S3 this way so it should be
quite a working approach but until that
uh Nixie search is going to do just a a
traditional segment replication because
for non-s Segment replication and go
into S3 without this prefetching thing
it's not going to work in practice no
one going to wait for 3 seconds until
your request executes but it's nice to
have this opportunity uh but if you do
some sort of a serverless search engine
it's like a dilemma so you can either go
for
um for for faster startup so you can uh
just uh start immediately and uh start
executing and sear serving this request
but you pay with the latency or you just
have some sort of a cold starting uh
case when you need to prefet the index
and start executing but with this uh
approach we took with Nix search when
everything is decoupled and trying to be
very simple it might be not that uh bad
but how can how far can you go with the
stateless approach with decoupling
everything and keeping things simple so
okay uh doing SE segment replication is
kind of know known feature in at least
in Lucine Community with enert search
and open search but can you also make
your cluster State external and
immutable and it sounds like a
um something forbidden that you do in a
search engines uh because what usually
how you usually change your application
configuration for the back end you Comm
something to the git uh that people are
doing pull requests there is cicd system
which runs tests and do some sort of
blue green or rolling deployment and
everything is fine you can do 100
deployments a day without just blinking
an eye what you usually do when you
change your cluster configuration uh for
a search engine so you send HTTP post
request to a prod cluster you pray that
everything goes good uh you see like
vibrations happening and you got a
message from your s about why things are
broken so can we do better can we maybe
make it uh just as it is usually done in
backend applications and not more like a
databases so we decided to do this as in
backend so this there is no API to
create index in Nixie search at all
there is no way to create index in Nixie
search apart just defining it in a
configuration file so that's the whole
index configuration so it's a hello
world index with two fields which one of
them is text field the second one is
integer field you can facet field or
sort over them and search is just a
vector search over this model so it
seems to be quite simple but then it
gives you an opportunity to do this back
and like deployment of your search
engine so it's not database anymore it's
just you know a regular backend
application yes data intensive yes
depends on the data but it's still more
or less
immutable so when you change your
configuration and your cicd system
starts deploying it the first thing that
we do is that to change the check the
compatibility that you actually can run
new configuration over the old index on
S3 if you can you just raise the health
check that you're fine and then just
continue accepting the traffic if you do
something which is forbidden with the
schema so you for example uh alter the
field in a non-compatible way and you
need to reindex it's not that bad
because your index is just a directory
on a block storage and your indexing is
not related to your search traffic so
instead of that you don't do like HTTP
post with your giant block of uh data to
your prod cluster uh because it's
usually in the most search engines the
same nodes are serving indexing and
searching workload and you need to be
very careful not to interfere with your
search because if you push too hard it
might break so you need to watch for
back pressure and it's kind of tough to
do uh but if you have index separately
and decoupled from your search you can
do it even offline because why not
uh it can be done in a separate service
so with NX search it's more like a
backend application you have your search
search cluster like this so there are
some search notes there is an index on
S3 there is an online indexer picking
messages from Kafka or whatever and you
decide to do the ray index and instead
of that you just R run a backend like a
like a Chron job or something like an
application which just reads everything
and writes a file you don't need cluster
for that it can be just you know a batch
job and when it's done reindexing it
just shuts down because why should you
keep it running and then you just
restart it in a more like a distributed
cluster configuration which just
continues updating this index and serve
the traffic so at that moment you have
two separate clusters you switch the
traffic if everything is fine and shut
down the first one you can not only do
blue green deployment you can roll this
deployment if you want because it's just
a configuration change so new notes will
Point into another directory on S3
serving similar but slightly different
index uh so you might say that okay nice
that you show it us to us but please
show us the actual code or not like the
code but
actual uh search engine itself so um
that's we're going to use a data set
called Amazon esci so it's like an
Amazon data set with products we have
categories here and number of ratings
that's how configuration looks like so
okay that's a title field which is text
and we're doing hybrid search with this
particular model like E5 Bas I very like
it we have a category which is a
repeated field and not just a singular
field and we have ratings to do fating
and filtering and uh as you might know
there are no configuration for S3
because I'm scared to do S3 over
conference Wi-Fi but if you want to do
this it it's just this snipp it so okay
our Searcher is going to be fully in
memory because it should be like fully
stateless why do we need storage if
index fits in memory our indexer can be
offloading it to disk and that's how you
configure the bucket and end point if
it's not Amazon uh okay the uh the dumb
way to die thing so uh we're running NX
search as a Java application but you
should really do it as a as a Docker
because that's how it's usually
supported and uh let's check out what we
can do that's we need to Define our
config file uh we need to Define the
index we're indexing it's esci and the
data the URL for the data is the data
set so after we do this something starts
happening uh it takes a couple of
seconds just to mostly load the model
and index your data we started indexing
uh no now we started yes there should be
a nice seci logo oh yeah so now so uh my
laptop is not as fast so you can see
that it's just doing inference on oh
it's
lagging okay so you see that it's doing
a lot of different things and uh while
it's indexing we can just enjoy the
logo my laptop was not as fast but it's
just spinning okay so we're done we can
just stop it and go and see what's in
our index directory so that's the whole
index a single segment nothing fancy 5
megabytes and um we can start start
start our search engine
uh well only need this this and I
search uh if you lazy there is also a
standalone mode which imitates the way
you do it with elastic or open search so
there is an API to push your documents
actually and it actually just does it as
elastic search but it's under the hood
it's still doing this thing with a
separate indexer and separate Searcher
and a directory synchronization but just
within a single process uh because if
you cannot live without pushing
documents into the cluster uh through
the rest API so we're starting our
search and it takes a couple of time
just to start and boom it started it has
some sort of a nice UI web interface
uh where you can just go and see your
index here and even maybe choose a title
and uh search over that and even facets
with filters and it's actually even
working but this demo is uh uh not about
just the UI we build but more about the
search request you can send so for first
thing we do is just doing search request
which looks very familiar to people
operating solar open search or elastic
search so let's search for
Spider-Man uh with this um search
request and it
actually wait a bit oh
host search end point and make it nice
okay so we got our search requests like
Spider-Man comingcoming skeleton costume
okay uh but because mostly Pro most
probably there's not that many documents
with about Spider-Man there you can also
not only search but as we're on lucene
it's very trivial to implement faceting
like an aggregations so we're going to
do the same
but with facets and we'll see how
familiar it might be because it's
Allen you see that that's our
aggregations over the categories field
it's mostly clothing and shoes for this
type of thing we can also do filters
because it's always seene it's very
trivial to implement and use and you can
just have it very in a very familiar way
this way so only things from the
category mask we got home Spider-Man
mask and some eye patches which are
technically also mask uh but if you are
on Lucine you can go further and even
have autocomplete suggestions it's a bit
different end point called
Suggest and you can get for the Spide
suggestion a couple of suggestions like
spider Spider-Man Spider-Man coming
huming spider sign spy Spa why not uh
but still it seems to be quite a
reasonable thing to see for this type of
thing but we went further and if you do
some modern technology it's not about
hybrid search but maybe some rag on top
of search results it also seems to be
very trivial to implement so let's do
our search and like was have a
Spider-Man search with a short summary
following search results blah blah blah
traditional Rock style um and we got it
here and we'll do some sort of uh it
takes some time because we're on my old
Linux laptop and we're doing on a CPU
and I know why it's so slow and it's
done on GPU it's usually a bit faster or
on a bit Modern Hardware so search
results provide various costumes and
accessor related to Spider-Man it can
also do streaming but it doesn't look
nice from the console so and the cool
thing is the um the impressive thing I'm
going to do is that just ask how much uh
is it like takes uh a lot of resources
or not to run NX search and we just
do it like this four GC wow 23
megabytes not bad for Java application
uh okay back to slides um we there are
some limitations of this approach of
course you can't it's not a general
purposed search engine which will fit
any possible uh search use case because
if you uh have a promise of having
everything stateless you will have
problem running this with Shing because
Shing assumes that your notes need to
know about existence of each other and
your index is distributed across the
notes so you can't just have sharding
with being fully stateless you need to
have like a contract with your s safe
and break the promise of being stateless
so we it doesn't mean that we'll never
Implement Charing support but as for now
we don't really see the way to implement
it without introducing any more
complexity into the search engine but
being honest in my past career uh uh in
95% of the cases you don't really need
sharding people people Shard because
they can because there is an API to do
sharding and that's what written in the
Docks but um in find in back my F5 years
there were about 2,000 e-commerce stores
and the largest was about 1 million
documents in the inventory in the liver
here it's also ballpark the same so we
do sharding because we can but usually
there is no reason why we do it and if
you need sharting in most cases if
either you're are like a big Tech like f
and Google and that's acceptable and
understandable but you probably can
build your own search engine without
help of me and or you do search not over
consumer facing search but it's more
like a developer facing search with
analyzes over logs or traces or events
and this is not what uh NX search is for
so it's more about for Consumer facing
search and you might also notice in our
uh in the demo that we're doing all this
uh inference locally it's also more like
a a personal decision that you need to
have as less uh external dependences as
possible because from the NX search
perspective it's just a single Locker
container you can run it on CPU you can
run it on GPU it will use gpus for
inference but at the end it doesn't
really need anything but just this
Docker container and the first pro of
this approach is that latency because
embedding inference for queries is like
5 milliseconds on a CPU for short
queries and I guess even the round trip
to your networking end point for
embedding provider is going to take much
longer and uh the embedding itself is
also not as fast as it can be so like
hundred of milliseconds that no problem
and the second thing is that your data
and your search queries you're not
sending them to open AI to just do
embedding yes they will never never
train models on your data but still
better to be safe but optionally there
are some providers like connectors to
open a if you really trust them uh and
um we're trying to uh do it locally to
have zero dependencies and uh with do
support Onix for embeddings and Onix
doesn't mean that it's something special
it's just a different format of the
model for the inference and you need a
oneliner with a python to convert your
pytorch model into your into your own
model it's like hug uh Accel no not
accelerate so it's something from
hugging face it's just a one liner to do
it we have a wrapper to do some
traditional oops some traditional things
like quantization and all that stuff but
you don't really need to use it even and
uh there are some things we not yet
implemented in Nixie search but it's
going to be like a low hanging fuit if
we have all the IND structure so like
right now we only do hybrid search like
lexical through Lucine and uh some
Vector search over HSV but it's all done
through Lucine there is no special
mechanics out of that it's just all
luine uh and we can feed the results
into generative model to build your like
rag on the top we also want to do a
ranking support because it's just yet
another flavor of your o enx model so
for to do this cross encoders on top so
it's going to be retrieve Rank and
summarized and option we have some sort
of external providers uh available but
it's not like this so as we can run
indexing separately and we can run it
technically some uh higher compute
budget and you can run it on a fixed
period of time you can do a lot of llm
driven processing for your documents
Corpus for example you can split it to
chunks you can do some sort of
summarization or like uh do some
contextual embedding for a contextual
embedding is that when you split a large
document you can prepend each chunk with
a summary of the whole document so each
chunk will know what's it's all about in
general or maybe do some category
detection uh out of your document
because you just ask llama running
locally okay is it like a dish or non
dish and uh you might wonder that okay
we we targeting clouds is it costly to
run but you know this G4 large with T4
GPU which is okay to run for is 300 a
month but you don't really need to run
it for the whole month it's just for
indexing so it's going to be very cost
effective at the end and some nice
things which are more like moonshots
because the main issue with the uh
current traditional search engines is
that if you got embedding model the same
you'll got the same search results on
doesn't really matter on which search
engine it's just the underlying Tech and
usually people do fine tuning but with
fine tuning it becomes very complicated
because you need training data and
usually you don't because uh it's very
expensive very long and complicated
process but you do have documents
because you're going to search over them
so you have documents why don't we
distill like a large model to generate
the queries and then out of the queries
and documents to generate negatives and
then F tune and underlying model it's
like a common uh Topic in different
conferences but what we're trying to do
right now is to train a specific model
to generate the square it's available
hugging phase it's usually uh like it's
a mistal model which is fine-tuned on
documents to predict the quiry so you
have a lot of such quiry document pairs
but you just uh turn
them like this and just predict a query
and not just some query like CHP does
but the real query what people use to
search this document but we found out
that sometimes it works in some
documents for some document purposes
sometimes it doesn't so we want to make
it more like you know know uh
predictable so you don't really throw a
coin uh and will it work or won't won't
work on your particular close data set
so right now it's kind of very um
unpredictable I can say so I can say
that if you want to try this expect a
bump you right so it's a
0.3.3 so version it doesn't mean that we
started from 0.3.3 just for this
conference there were previous versions
um but some features might be missing
like uh sorting it doesn't mean that
it's hard to implement that's the issue
that it's uh very easy and boring to
implement because it's just you know
Lucine you just need to have an API for
that and it works but uh it's not as fun
as implementing Rec for example um docs
documents are imperfect but we they
there are docs and there might be
breaking changes but usually these
breaking changes are related to The
Reason like they're justified by the
values so for example when this doing
rag we broke the configuration file but
still it's uh as you are breaking just
the syntax on configuration file your
cicd system W won't let you deploy and
break your cluster so it's not as bad as
it can be uh okay so for the links it's
available on GitHub fully open source
there is a document micro site where you
can just go and check out the documents
and surprisingly they are documents but
it's like if you're lazy to submit an
issue
um yeah conference website conference
Wi-Fi is risky yeah so it doesn't
doesn't seem to work H because I need to
connect to
this I connected to the dongle
whoa okay
so the are docks so and there are quite
a lot of them and surprisingly you might
find that at the beginning there are
plenty of docks and if you go further
further to deployment you might find
that some of them are missing but that's
fine because uh we're it's more like an
open source project which is not
sponsored by some company so you should
expect this type of situations but
anyway you can go to slack and ask a
question and get an answer uh so that's
all for me uh so uh if you have any
questions you're
welcome fantastic what a great talk to K
us on day two thank you very much Roman
so do we have any questions
yes yeah thanks for the talk looks like
a cool project uh I I kind of I guess I
understand the sharding thing but I
think some kind of partitioning would
still be nice let's say if you would
have a filter and push that down to the
fetching right where you let's say have
a doop HFS style petitioning things did
you consider this for sharding and
partitioning yes we do consider but it's
still if you're if you're stateless how
would your node a will reach the node B
what's does it even exist so they need
to somehow communicate to each other
maybe through S3 or some internal
protocol to communicate and then it
introduces State inside of your nose
because the if if they speak someone
needs to be master and make the decision
who owns what shart so for example you
have two shards you start a note and
okay what Shard should you choose a or b
maybe there is already someone handling
a then you need to pick B but before
that you need to ask the cluster okay
what's your opinion which shart should I
choose so that's kind of the problem it
can be implemented in a way that NOS
won't speak to each other for example in
S3 you can do something like compare and
swap through eags which is atomic which
is seems very strange thing to do but
technically if you have a comparing swap
primitive you can build any distributed
system on top of that but um it still
seems very fragile and uh I personally
don't really need
sharding and as I'm building this for
for myself and um why why should we
complicate this situation right now so
maybe in the future so we know like it
can be done in a specific way but uh
right now
some usually if you need charting you
have a lot of documents how many
documents you have in your production
index staying in the e-commerce setting
where you have one index but maybe there
are stores inside of that right that you
want to just push down as a predicate
and then is actually for me more of
actual data fetching a problem not NE
necessarily A State Management problem
you know you know what I mean so you
have the URLs and yes you only want to
fetch certain keys from S3 that have the
store inside ah then you can have
separate indices for thinking yes
probably you just say
that um but still I guess from
organizational point of view it would be
nice to have this inside one index you
know but I I get the point uh in my past
company at find if5 got the same
situation originally it was one giant
cluster handling all the documents but
usually you don't want to be that fair
to your tenants so some of them need to
have uh like you need to be more fair to
someone so you just because they're
paying you more so they have more
resources and the ones which are not
paying you are paying you less you get
less resources so you need to some sort
of control if you have separate indices
for them it's up to you you can set
number of replicas per index and that's
fine if it's just a single case space
that's very hard to say that okay this
prefix is g to more replication than
that
prefix okay um anyone on the online chat
please type your questions into the zoom
chat if you have a question uh any other
questions from the
room great talk thanks um you mentioned
that you still have the latency issues
uh um on the first read but also later
because of uh you know I think your
design is uh more towards like uh read
through cache right so when you read you
so the implementation of the cache in
the directory is read through and you
also mentioned the other approach could
be kind of like a right through cache
where uh you know I mean you you you
prefetch everything uh that's what we do
uh that you have and uh okay and I
didn't catch then how how low your L
latency becomes because it's all Lucine
running on the dis
so the latency there are Lucine
benchmarks so you expect very similar
latency for this type of queries but
usually just a matter of milliseconds it
depends on your index size or your dis
storage but you shouldn't really expect
anything different because it's all
Lucen cool thank you any further
questions from the room
the one oh
yes hi um is this supposed to run on uh
either as lambas or on ec2 or like you
still technically yes so it can work on
Lambda but the thing is that the Lambda
startup time is going to be high because
you need to fetch the index to the
Lambda
uh that's not what you usually do within
the Lambda but technically that's like a
perfect fit for the Lambda if you can
keep this Lambda running at least one
just to handle some occasional requests
which are not happening frequently and
you just scale up in case if there is
more request than you prefer than you
expect then yes it will can work with
the Lambda it's just a Docker container
or maybe for the
inest for inje yes but I think for
ingestion it depends on how sensitive
you to this indexing latency so in many
forers cases you're absolutely not
sensitive to latency so you can wait and
you can just have a batch job just to
update your index every 10 minutes you
start it for like a 30 seconds process
the updates and shut it down so it can
run in this type of configuration quite
happily or in some cases there can be
even longer latency but you can just
keep it running also in a Lambda
I think we had one more question over
here who who had the hand up
yes great talk thanks uh what about cash
and validation so if if you have
continuously updated index like what
what would be the best approach to
validate the cach and so it's not doing
any external caching apart from the one
provided by Lucine but in Lucine as far
as I know cash is tied to a segment
and you're not changing segments you're
just adding segments or removing
segments so then it doesn't mean that
you're going to invalidate search
results for a particular segment if you
update uh your index so you update a
single document it just gets a small
segment on top of your large segment
with 1 million documents and when you do
search in Lucine it's actually do two
searches over each of the segment the
search over the old segment is going to
be fast and cached the search over small
segment is going to be non-cached but
then you collect and merge the results
and you're done but again it's not my
implementation it's all happening under
the H and
Lucine okay I think do we have any
further
questions right okay so let's thank
Roman